<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Janice in SG</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://janicesg.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-06-06T15:53:21.111Z</updated>
  <id>https://janicesg.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Janice Zhao</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Switzerland Trip in 2018</title>
    <link href="https://janicesg.github.io/switzerland-2018/"/>
    <id>https://janicesg.github.io/switzerland-2018/</id>
    <published>2020-05-09T11:48:22.708Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-06T15:53:21.111Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h2><p>I went to Switzerland on a two-week’s personal trip with my friend CM in the spring of 2018. Switzerland, is like a ‘Jungfrau’, who impressed me, a visitor from afar, with the breath-taking view and hospitable people. I was trying to be a vegetarian back then, so CM and I only had one meal with her old school friend in a local restaurant. We cooked and packed our meals for the rest of the trip, which is why there won’t be a lot of typical exotic food pictures below.<br>We planned to tour the whole country within 15 days, so we rent an airbnb studio in Basel, a small town located in the middle of Switzerland, and is accessible to all the tourist attractions via trains. Yet due to the fact that most of the tourist attractions are scattered around the country, and are 2~3 hrs away from our airbnb, we had to get up at 4:30am and leave the house at 5:30am to catch the earliest train, so that we wouldn’t behind our schedule. So the trip was actually quite tiring, not mentioning the wake up hours, we did a lot of hiking too.<br>CM is a great planner, and she managed to plan for most the day trips. She even wrote down the timings of each trains that we should take, and in case of missing any, she wrote down the previous and next train timing as well.</p><h2 id="Lugano"><a href="#Lugano" class="headerlink" title="Lugano"></a>Lugano</h2><p>We went to Lugano, the capital of the southest Cantone Ticino bordered with Italy via train, and it took about 3hrs from where we stay.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/lugano.jpg" width="720px"><br>The train station was high in the mountain, and we need to walk down the hill to the city.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/luganoBell.jpg" width="720px"><br>Before we boarded for our boat trip, we bumped into an open area event happening at the market center. There were performances of kids, including ballet, kpop dancing, and a children orchestra performance.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/dance.jpg" width="720px"><br>We took a boat to tour around the lake bordering with Italy, and the flag is even italian.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/italianflag.jpg" width="720px"><br>The boat trip lasted about 4hrs, our original plan was to visit the village across, however there was no time, thus we decided to walk around lugano for a while.</p><p>The Gelato is pretty authentic, they even offered Vegan flavor for CM. I got an vanilla flavor, and I had to admit it melts very fast in the middle of the hot early summer day.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/gelato_1.jpg" width="720px"></p><p>To be continued……</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h2 id=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Introduction&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went to Switzerland on a two
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="switzerland" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/switzerland/"/>
    
      <category term="travel" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/travel/"/>
    
      <category term="2018" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/2018/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
