<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Janice in SG</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://janicesg.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-07-12T14:20:05.810Z</updated>
  <id>https://janicesg.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Janice Zhao</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Zurich, Switzerland (Thanks,Google Translation)</title>
    <link href="https://janicesg.github.io/Switzerland-zurich-english-version/"/>
    <id>https://janicesg.github.io/Switzerland-zurich-english-version/</id>
    <published>2020-07-12T14:14:35.382Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-12T14:20:05.810Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Preface"><a href="#Preface" class="headerlink" title="Preface"></a>Preface</h3><p>I took a two-week personal trip with my friend CM in May 2018. The natural scenery in Switzerland left a deep impression on me, and the breathtaking scenery became my most beautiful memory in 2018. At that time I was thinking about being a vegetarian, so CM and I only had a meal with her old classmates in a local restaurant. In the following journey, most of the time we cooked the food in advance, packed the food in a sealed lunch box, and ate it on the return train, so this travelogue does not have many typical exotic food photos.</p><p>We plan to visit the entire country in 15 days, so we rented an airbnb studio in Basel, a small town in central Switzerland, from where you can take a train to all tourist attractions. But since most tourist attractions are scattered all over the country and about 2 to 3 hours away from our Airbnb, we have to get up at 4:30am and leave the house at 5:30am in order to catch the earliest train, so we Will not fall behind the schedule. Therefore, this trip is actually very tiring. Another reason, of course, is that we did a lot of hiking.</p><p>CM is an excellent planner, she made plans for most day trips. The itinerary is divided into days, so that it can be adjusted in time according to weather changes. She is a super-experienced trip planner, and even wrote down the time of every train we should take, and in case of missing any time, she also wrote down the time of the previous and next train. So the entire trip is full of schedules, and there is no missed train or even a temporary change of plan.</p><p>This travelogue will mainly share the travel experience and some beautiful photos taken with me. The epidemic is trapped at home now. Recalling the situation at that time is also a cloud travel. This also fully proves that I am a procrastinating patient in organizing travel notes, severely.</p><h3 id="1-Departure"><a href="#1-Departure" class="headerlink" title="1. Departure"></a>1. Departure</h3><p>Our ticket is from Singapore to Doha, Qatar, the terminal Zurich, about ten hours.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_050901.jpg?token=ADYYPSXDJECH2G5WSASBLF27BMGXU" alt=""><br>When I stopped at Doha International Airport, there was a huge bear, and I didn’t know what mascot it was, so I just patted it.</p><p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_010126.jpg?token=ADYYPSRMH3EIS4UW4PMT35K7BMGX6" alt=""></p><h3 id="2-Arrival-in-Zurich"><a href="#2-Arrival-in-Zurich" class="headerlink" title="2. Arrival in Zurich"></a>2. Arrival in Zurich</h3><p>When our plane landed at Zurich Airport at about 6 in the morning, although the two of them slept all the way, they were still very excited when they arrived, and immediately woke up. Before getting off the plane, I painted a special painting in the toilet. Light make-up, otherwise the whole train is really very lacking. After getting off the plane, there are many people in the customs, but unfortunately we don’t have the EU fast track to go. After passing the customs, we took the luggage and took the subway to the central train station.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_094750.jpg?token=ADYYPSX2AQA2NYSBPJ7TTWK7BMGW4" alt=""><br>Swiss subways and trains are quite similar, and there are newspapers left by passengers on the seats. Because Zurich is in the German-speaking area, the newspapers are also in German. However, I couldn’t understand it at the time. Although I can only know a few words now, which one The German God can translate what is said.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_083413.jpg?token=ADYYPSQA6ISTOPILC4M5F3S7BMGS6" alt=""><br>When we arrived at the central train station, we went to help CM to buy snow boots, but the results were obtained too early, and the store did not open the door. I had to drag the big box and walk back to the train station. This is the Zurich Central Station.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_113415.jpg" alt=""><br>When we were struggling to find a locker, CM had the courage to ask a little brother who sold fruits. As a result, the little brother was very nice. Not only did he take us to change the change, but he also took us to find the locker and help us lift it. Put the box in the locker, and finally took us around the station and left contact information with each other. The day after that, I was lucky to travel with Zurich together again. I was really fortunate. Until now, we have followed each other on Instagram.<br>Things are set, the two of us go to the first attraction, Uetliberg.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_095627.jpg?token=ADYYPSX42HAXXAMRNRUKVMK7BMGXE" alt=""></p><p>This is a mountain near Zurich, about 870 meters high, but you can take the train to Uetliberg station and you can start hiking. It’s a pity that we went early that day, and there was light rain before, so the smog is a bit like being in a fairyland.</p><p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_101857.jpg?token=ADYYPSTRZRV32SSR32OVTOS7BMGWW" alt=""><br>Going down from the mountain, the two of us took the boat to ETH, the best polytechnic in Switzerland. Along the way, we sat in the window seat and took a look at the view of Zurich along the lake.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_133437.jpg?token=ADYYPSTI3CRWJZKP2FDWTTS7BMGWQ" alt=""><br>Interestingly, each pier has a specially designed flag. I don’t know if it’s a pier flag. The Swiss really like the flag, and they have to design a flag for him. It can be seen that there are many boats moored on the shore, and a few are driving. I have to sigh that Zurich’s people are really comfortable living by the mountains and rivers, but the cost of living is really expensive. Sure enough, the mountains, waters, and coziness are almost as good as the Swiss franc.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_124746.jpg?token=ADYYPSTTTIUTE5RDJQA5WSK7BMGUU" alt=""><br>CM’s university exchange friends are studying for a Ph.D. in ETH. They agreed to meet in advance today, so we made an appointment in ETH’s main square. The sun was warm at the time, many students were chatting on the square, and there were also drinks. When the two of us were waiting for our friends, we also bought a drink for ourselves.<br>This is a building of ETH. At that time, there was a group of students who followed the teacher to visit outside, perhaps to talk about history or architecture.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_135527.jpg" alt=""><br>ETH is on a hill, so from its square, the whole city has a panoramic view.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_140242.jpg?token=ADYYPSRYIOFWPKKJ6XVC3O27BMG3O" alt=""><br>The meeting between the French university and the professor was delayed, and I and CM decided to go around in the university. This is a university store, also known as a shop.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_150847.jpg?token=ADYYPSV6D5G36ZC7D4OAHBK7BMGUE" alt=""><br>Take pictures in a corner where the sun can’t find.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_153524.jpg?token=ADYYPSXQEDUBQB5E5RKBUWK7BMGT6" alt=""></p><p>CM suggested that we take the small mountain train. I was shocked by the Swiss railway technology for the first time, although I was always shocked during this journey. The small train only takes a few minutes one way, and the two of us sat back and forth four times, like a kid who has never seen the world with a big heart. The next one is looking up, and the other is looking down. The little train is really fun to climb.</p><p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_150143.jpg?token=ADYYPSXGQH7PEQBDLTDCT5K7BMGU4" alt=""><br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/up.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Finally waiting for the French university bully, we decided to take a walk in the old town. The old town is all stone roads, and the streets are lined with elegantly decorated old shops.<br>After passing a bridge, the weather was amazing.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_162456.jpg?token=ADYYPSURVUYPY2N7W2CMXHK7BMG3I" alt=""><br>Notice the double-roofed church on the right side of the picture above. We bought a ticket and climbed all the way up. The staircase is a narrow wooden spiral staircase, which is breathless to climb, but the scenery above is really good.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_155322.jpg?token=ADYYPSUAX56PLPMD3GVHM7C7BMG24" alt=""><br>It was about four o’clock when we came down from the church. We decided to eat. It was the only meal we had in a restaurant. We were not full at all. I really felt that the price of Switzerland was higher than SG.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/receipt.jpg" alt=""></p><p>After the doctoral friend had a football match, we separated. I took the package with CM to catch the train and returned to the base in Basel. I will stay here for the next few days. But there was no Wi-Fi on the first night, we went downstairs to the Wi-Fi of the supermarket and contacted the landlord. The landlord was on vacation abroad, saying that there was a technical problem with an operator, and it would be fixed the next day, so we two You can only take a bath early to rest and recuperate for tomorrow’s travel.</p><p>The following travel notes will be written slowly, don’t forget to pay attention and like.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h3 id=&quot;Preface&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Preface&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Preface&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Preface&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took a two-week personal trip with my friend CM 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Travel" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/categories/Travel/"/>
    
    
      <category term="switzerland" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/switzerland/"/>
    
      <category term="travel" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/travel/"/>
    
      <category term="2018" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/2018/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>瑞士 苏黎世 壹</title>
    <link href="https://janicesg.github.io/Switzerland-Zurich/"/>
    <id>https://janicesg.github.io/Switzerland-Zurich/</id>
    <published>2020-07-12T12:58:05.968Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-12T13:50:21.014Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="序言"><a href="#序言" class="headerlink" title="序言"></a>序言</h3><p>于2018年五月份与朋友CM进行了为期两周的个人旅行。瑞士的自然风光给我留下了深刻的印象，以令人叹为观止的景色成为了我2018年的最美回忆。那时我正想当素食主义者，所以CM和我在当地一家餐馆只和她的老同学吃了一顿饭。在接下来的旅程中，大部分的时间我们都提前把食物煮熟，用密封饭盒将食物打包好了， 在回程的火车上吃，所以本篇游记没有很多典型的异国美食照片。</p><p>我们计划在15天内游览整个国家，因此我们在瑞士中部的一个小镇 巴塞尔Basel租了一个airbnb的studio，从这里可以乘火车前往所有旅游景点。但是由于大多数旅游景点分散在全国各地，并且距离我们的 Airbnb 约2至3个小时，因此我们不得不在凌晨4:30起床并在凌晨5:30离开房屋，以便赶上最早的火车，这样我们就不会落后于时间表。因此，这次旅行实际上很累，另外一个原因当然也包括我们做了很多Hiking。</p><p>CM是一位出色的策划者，她为大多数一日游做了计划。把行程以天来分，这样就可以根据天气变化适时调整。她是一个超级有经验的trip planner，甚至写下了我们应该乘坐的每趟火车的时刻，并且在错过任何时刻的情况下，她还写下了上一趟和下一趟火车的时刻。所以整个旅行都是满满的行程安排，也没有错过火车或者甚至临时改变计划。</p><p>这篇游记会主要分享旅行中的见闻，和我拍的一些美照，现在疫情被困在家里，回忆一下当时的情况也算云旅游了。这也充分证明我在整理游记方面是个拖延症患者，重度那种。</p><h2 id="1-出发"><a href="#1-出发" class="headerlink" title="1. 出发"></a>1. 出发</h2><p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_050901.jpg?token=ADYYPSXDJECH2G5WSASBLF27BMGXU" alt=""></p><p>我们的机票是新加坡出发经停卡塔尔多哈，终点站苏黎世，大概十几个小时。在多哈国际机场经停的时候，有一个巨大的熊熊，不是很懂是什么吉祥物，就随手拍了一下。</p><p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_010126.jpg?token=ADYYPSRMH3EIS4UW4PMT35K7BMGX6" alt=""></p><h2 id="2-到达苏黎世"><a href="#2-到达苏黎世" class="headerlink" title="2.到达苏黎世"></a>2.到达苏黎世</h2><p>我们的飞机降落在苏黎世机场的时候是清晨6点左右，两个人虽然一路睡的不好，但是一到地方还是非常激动的，立刻清醒了，下飞机前，我还在厕所里专门画了个淡妆，不然一路舟车劳顿真的非常没有气色。下飞机过海关人山人海，可惜我们没有EU的快速通道可以走，顺利过海关之后我们拿了行李，坐地铁去中心火车站。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_094750.jpg?token=ADYYPSX2AQA2NYSBPJ7TTWK7BMGW4" alt=""><br>瑞士地铁和火车蛮像，座位上还有乘客留下的报纸，因为苏黎世在德语区，所以报纸也是德语的，然而当时的我完全看不懂，虽然现在只能认识一点点词，有哪位德语大神可以翻译一下这讲了什么。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_083413.jpg?token=ADYYPSQA6ISTOPILC4M5F3S7BMGS6" alt=""><br>到了中心火车站， 我们先去帮CM买雪地靴，结果取得太早，店都没有开门。只好拖着大箱子再走回火车站，这就是 苏黎世 中心火车站啦。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_113415.jpg" alt=""><br>在我们千辛万苦找锁柜而不得的时候，CM鼓足勇气问了一个卖水果的小哥哥，结果小哥哥非常nice，不仅带我们去换零钱，还带我们找到锁柜，帮我们抬箱子放进锁柜，最后还带我们在车站外面转了转，并且互留了联系方式。之后的一天有幸又一起同游了苏黎世，真的非常有缘分了，直到现在我们还互相follow Instagram。<br>东西放好了，我们俩去往第一个景点，Uetliberg.<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_095627.jpg?token=ADYYPSX42HAXXAMRNRUKVMK7BMGXE" alt=""></p><p>这是一个 苏黎世 近郊的山，大概870米高，但是可以坐火车坐到Uetliberg站，就可以开始hiking了。可惜当天我们去的早，并且之前下过小雨，所以烟雾蒙蒙，有点像置身仙境。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_101857.jpg?token=ADYYPSTRZRV32SSR32OVTOS7BMGWW" alt=""></p><p>从山上下来，我们俩就坐上游船赶往ETH， 瑞士最好的理工学院。一路上，我们坐在靠窗的座位，把 苏黎世 的沿湖景色看了一遍。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_133437.jpg?token=ADYYPSTI3CRWJZKP2FDWTTS7BMGWQ" alt=""><br>有趣的是，每个码头都有一个特殊设计的旗子，不懂是不是码头旗。 瑞士人真的超喜欢旗子，什么都要专门设计一个旗子给他。可以看到有很多船泊在岸边，也有几艘在行驶，不得不感叹苏黎世的人生活依山傍水真的很惬意，但是架不住它生活成本真的贵啊。果然还是好山好水好惬意，只差点瑞士法郎。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_124746.jpg?token=ADYYPSTTTIUTE5RDJQA5WSK7BMGUU" alt=""><br>CM的大学交换的朋友在ETH读博士，他俩提前约好今天要见一面，于是我们就约在ETH的大广场。当时阳光暖人，很多学生在广场上聊天，还有卖酒水的，我们俩在等朋友来的时候，也自己买了一杯来喝，不错，很清凉。<br>这是ETH的一栋大楼，当时还有一群学生跟着老师在外面参观，可能是讲历史或者建筑。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_135527.jpg" alt=""><br>ETH在小山上，所以从它的广场上望，整个城市的景色尽收眼底。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_140242.jpg?token=ADYYPSRYIOFWPKKJ6XVC3O27BMG3O" alt=""><br>法国大学霸跟教授的会议delay了，我跟CM决定在大学里面转转。这是一个大学商店，也就是小卖部。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_150847.jpg?token=ADYYPSV6D5G36ZC7D4OAHBK7BMGUE" alt=""><br>躲在一个太阳找不到的角落拍照。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_153524.jpg?token=ADYYPSXQEDUBQB5E5RKBUWK7BMGT6" alt=""></p><p>CM建议我们去坐上山小火车，我第一次被瑞士高超的铁路技术震惊，虽然这旅程里一直被震惊。小火车单程只要几分钟，我俩来来回回坐了四趟，像极了没见过世面的玩心大发的孩子。下面一张是上山望，一张是下山望。小火车咯噔咯噔爬山真的太好玩了。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_150143.jpg?token=ADYYPSXGQH7PEQBDLTDCT5K7BMGU4" alt=""><br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/up.jpg" alt=""></p><p>终于等来了 法国大学霸，我们决定在老城区散散步。老城区都是石子路，街道两侧是装潢很典雅的老店，上上下下，路起起伏伏，走的有点喘。<br>经过了一个大桥，天气好的不得了。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_162456.jpg?token=ADYYPSURVUYPY2N7W2CMXHK7BMG3I" alt=""><br>注意上图右侧的双顶教堂，我们买票一路爬到了上面，楼梯是窄窄的木质旋转楼梯，爬的气喘吁吁，但是上面的风景真的很好。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/20180518_155322.jpg?token=ADYYPSUAX56PLPMD3GVHM7C7BMG24" alt=""><br>从教堂下来就大概四点了，我们决定去吃东西，也是我俩唯一一顿在餐馆吃的饭，完全没吃饱，真切感受到瑞士物价名不虚传。<br><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/janicesg/blogPicBed/master/img/receipt.jpg" alt=""></p><p>之后博士朋友有足球比赛，我们就分开了，我跟CM取包赶火车，回到了在basel的根据地，接下来的几天都会呆在这里。可是第一天晚上就没有Wi-Fi，我们下楼去蹭超市的Wi-Fi联系到了房东，房东正在国外度假，说有一个运营商出了技术问题，第二天就会修好，所以我们俩只能早早洗澡休息，为明天的出行养精蓄锐。</p><p>接下来的游记会慢慢写，别忘了关注点赞。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h3 id=&quot;序言&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#序言&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;序言&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;序言&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;于2018年五月份与朋友CM进行了为期两周的个人旅行。瑞士的自然风光给我留下了深刻的印象，以令人叹为观止的景色成为了我2018年的最美回忆。
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Travel" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/categories/Travel/"/>
    
    
      <category term="switzerland" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/switzerland/"/>
    
      <category term="travel" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/travel/"/>
    
      <category term="2018" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/2018/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>关于个人成长的思考（20200611）-谷歌机翻版</title>
    <link href="https://janicesg.github.io/some-thoughts-20200611-chinese-version/"/>
    <id>https://janicesg.github.io/some-thoughts-20200611-chinese-version/</id>
    <published>2020-06-12T06:38:58.267Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T07:26:41.208Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>懒得一字一句的翻译，就只能请谷歌帮忙翻译啦。<br>英文版在这里：  <a href="/some-thoughts-20200611/" title="Thoughts on personal growth（20200611）">Thoughts on personal growth（20200611）</a></p><h2 id="介绍"><a href="#介绍" class="headerlink" title="介绍"></a>介绍</h2><p>最近，我与我的经理和导师进行了一对一的交流，这里有些想法值得一提。</p><h2 id="影响力和说服力"><a href="#影响力和说服力" class="headerlink" title="影响力和说服力"></a>影响力和说服力</h2><p>成功地建立自己的影响力意味着您的老板和同事在关键的决策点上接受您的想法。我观察到，有些人在需要做出决定时会退后一步，但是一旦做出决定，他们就会抱怨该决定很糟糕，而他对此并不满意. 让我们假设一个会议场景，其中有几个建议供老板选择。如果他选择了一个由极有说服力的人吹捧的建议，尽管这在您看来是最糟糕的建议，但您仍然要承担决策的后果, 因为您没有尝试介入。</p><p>因此，在有正确观点的情况下，尝试整合演讲，说服，销售和谈判技巧以说服他人。逐步建立正面形象和品牌。虽然这些技能不是立即获得的，但是有了这种头脑，随着时间的流逝，如果不断地进行练习，它会逐渐提高。</p><h2 id="先问-为什么，再问-做什么"><a href="#先问-为什么，再问-做什么" class="headerlink" title="先问 为什么，再问 做什么"></a>先问 为什么，再问 做什么</h2><p>我知道讲WHY和WHAT的关系已经很陈词滥调，但只是想根据我的个人经验添加一些要点。例如，由于我在一个大团队中工作，经理通常在团队成员之间分配工作负载。当我被分配了一个jira时，通常是在一项服务中开发一项功能，最近，我倾向于将自己局限于分配的工作，而又不想了解其他人在做什么。但是，成长并能够在团队中承担更大责任的关键在于您了解端到端领域知识和业务流程的能力。将自己限制在一个狭窄的聚光灯下将禁止学习和理解全局，不利于个人成长。</p><p>因此，</p><ul><li>在分配任务时，始终积极地问为什么必须以某种方式完成任务，并与利益相关者从多个角度来理解它，包括业务分析师（BA），项目经理，客户。深入研究“什么”，“何时”和“如何”的细节，以了解所做出的决策，并有意见可对这些决策提供反馈。</li><li>其次，与队友交谈以了解他们正在做什么，以了解整个情况。</li><li>第三，进行产品修复时，即使您修复的是一行代码，也不要假设现有代码可以很好地与您的修复一起使用。始终仔细检查代码，并与BA核对预期行为。</li></ul><h2 id="让自己可见"><a href="#让自己可见" class="headerlink" title="让自己可见"></a>让自己可见</h2><p>简单粗暴的来讲，可见性会影响您未来的机会。在拥有100多名员工的部门中，您需要通过帮助他人并积极参加活动，成为他人需要解决问题或者提供建议的首选人。抓住机会向他人展示您的专业知识，并让他们尤其是管理团队认识到您的潜力。</p><p>让我们一起反思，总结和成长：)</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;懒得一字一句的翻译，就只能请谷歌帮忙翻译啦。&lt;br&gt;英文版在这里：  &lt;a href=&quot;/some-thoughts-20200611/&quot; title=&quot;Thoughts on personal growth（20200611）&quot;&gt;Thoughts on personal 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Career" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/categories/Career/"/>
    
    
      <category term="影响力" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/%E5%BD%B1%E5%93%8D%E5%8A%9B/"/>
    
      <category term="个人品牌" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E5%93%81%E7%89%8C/"/>
    
      <category term="说服力" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/%E8%AF%B4%E6%9C%8D%E5%8A%9B/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Thoughts on personal growth（20200611）</title>
    <link href="https://janicesg.github.io/some-thoughts-20200611/"/>
    <id>https://janicesg.github.io/some-thoughts-20200611/</id>
    <published>2020-06-11T09:05:53.021Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-13T14:13:33.982Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chinese Version：  <a href="/some-thoughts-20200611-chinese-version/" title="关于个人成长的思考（20200611）-谷歌机翻版">关于个人成长的思考（20200611）-谷歌机翻版</a></p><h2 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h2><p>Recently I had 1-on-1 catch ups with my manager and mentors, here are some thoughts worth noting down for my record.  </p><h2 id="Influence-and-Persuasion"><a href="#Influence-and-Persuasion" class="headerlink" title="Influence and Persuasion"></a>Influence and Persuasion</h2><p>To build one’s influence successfully means your bosses and peers buy in your ideas at critical decision points. I have observed that some people step back when decisions need to be made, but once decisions are made, they groan that the decision is poor, and he is not happy with it. Hypothetically, Let’s assume a scenario where several proposals are for the boss to pick. If he chooses one proposal touted by someone who is very good at persuasion, although it is the worst proposal in your opinion, you still have to bear with the consequences of decision made. Because you don’t try to step in. </p><p>Therefore, lean in when with a valid perspective, but try to integrate presentation, persuasion, selling, and negotiation skills to convince others. Gradually, the positive image and branding will build up. These skills are not acquired instantly, but with this mindset in head, it should gradually improve over time with consistent practice. </p><h2 id="Ask-WHY-then-WHAT"><a href="#Ask-WHY-then-WHAT" class="headerlink" title="Ask WHY, then WHAT"></a>Ask WHY, then WHAT</h2><p>I know the WHY and WHAT are already cliche, but just want to add some takeaways based on my personal experience. For example, because I work in a big team, and it is common for manager to split workloads among team members. when I was assigned with a jira, normally it is to develop a feature in one service, recently I tend to limit myself to assigned work, without wanting to learn about what others are doing. But the key to grow and be able to take on bigger responsibility in a team lies in your capability to understand the domain knowledge and business flows end to end. Limiting yourself to a narrow spotlight will prohibit learning and understanding the big picture, and detrimental to personal growth.</p><p>Therefore,</p><ul><li>When assigned with tasks, always actively ask why it has to be done in certain way, approach stakeholders to understand it from multiple perspectives, including Business Analyst(BA), Program Manager, Client. Dive into details on WHAT, WHEN and HOW, to learn about the decisions made, and have an opinion to give feedback on those decisions. </li><li>Secondly, talk with teammates to understand what they are working on to learn about the whole picture.</li><li>Thirdly, when making product fix, don’t assume the existing code will work with your fix perfectly well, even though you fix is one line of code. Always carefully scrutinize the code and check with BA on the expected behavior. </li></ul><h2 id="Make-yourself-visible"><a href="#Make-yourself-visible" class="headerlink" title="Make yourself visible"></a>Make yourself visible</h2><p>Visibility impacts your future opportunities, put it in a blunt but simple way. In a department with 100+ employees, become the go-to person of others by helping them and actively participating in events. Grab the opportunity to present your expertise to others, and let them especially management teams recognize your potential. </p><p>Let’s reflect, summarize, and grow together :)</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Chinese Version：  &lt;a href=&quot;/some-thoughts-20200611-chinese-version/&quot; title=&quot;关于个人成长的思考（20200611）-谷歌机翻版&quot;&gt;关于个人成长的思考（20200611）-谷歌机翻版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Career" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/categories/Career/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Spotlight" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/Spotlight/"/>
    
      <category term="Influence" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/Influence/"/>
    
      <category term="Persuasion" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/Persuasion/"/>
    
      <category term="Personal Branding" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/Personal-Branding/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Switzerland Trip in 2018</title>
    <link href="https://janicesg.github.io/switzerland-2018/"/>
    <id>https://janicesg.github.io/switzerland-2018/</id>
    <published>2020-05-09T11:48:22.708Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T06:27:33.247Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h2><p>I went to Switzerland on a two-week’s personal trip with my friend CM in the spring of 2018. Switzerland, is like a ‘Jungfrau’, who impressed me, a visitor from afar, with the breath-taking view and hospitable people. I was trying to be a vegetarian back then, so CM and I only had one meal with her old school friend in a local restaurant. We cooked and packed our meals for the rest of the trip, which is why there won’t be a lot of typical exotic food pictures below.<br>We planned to tour the whole country within 15 days, so we rent an airbnb studio in Basel, a small town located in the middle of Switzerland, and is accessible to all the tourist attractions via trains. Yet due to the fact that most of the tourist attractions are scattered around the country, and are 2~3 hrs away from our airbnb, we had to get up at 4:30am and leave the house at 5:30am to catch the earliest train, so that we wouldn’t behind our schedule. So the trip was actually quite tiring, not mentioning the wake up hours, we did a lot of hiking too.<br>CM is a great planner, and she managed to plan for most the day trips. She even wrote down the timings of each trains that we should take, and in case of missing any, she wrote down the previous and next train timing as well.</p><h2 id="Lugano"><a href="#Lugano" class="headerlink" title="Lugano"></a>Lugano</h2><p>We went to Lugano, the capital of the southest Cantone Ticino bordered with Italy via train, and it took about 3hrs from where we stay.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/lugano.jpg" width="720px"><br>The train station was high in the mountain, and we need to walk down the hill to the city.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/luganoBell.jpg" width="720px"><br>Before we boarded for our boat trip, we bumped into an open area event happening at the market center. There were performances of kids, including ballet, kpop dancing, and a children orchestra performance.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/dance.jpg" width="720px"><br>We took a boat to tour around the lake bordering with Italy, and the flag is even italian.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/italianflag.jpg" width="720px"><br>The boat trip lasted about 4hrs, our original plan was to visit the village across, however there was no time, thus we decided to walk around lugano for a while.</p><p>The Gelato is pretty authentic, they even offered Vegan flavor for CM. I got an vanilla flavor, and I had to admit it melts very fast in the middle of the hot early summer day.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/gelato_1.jpg" width="720px"></p><p>To be continued……</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h2 id=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Introduction&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went to Switzerland on a two
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Travel" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/categories/Travel/"/>
    
    
      <category term="switzerland" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/switzerland/"/>
    
      <category term="travel" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/travel/"/>
    
      <category term="2018" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/2018/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
