<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Janice in SG</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://janicesg.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-06-12T07:26:41.208Z</updated>
  <id>https://janicesg.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Janice Zhao</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>关于个人成长的思考（20200611）-谷歌机翻版</title>
    <link href="https://janicesg.github.io/some-thoughts-20200611-chinese-version/"/>
    <id>https://janicesg.github.io/some-thoughts-20200611-chinese-version/</id>
    <published>2020-06-12T06:38:58.267Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T07:26:41.208Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>懒得一字一句的翻译，就只能请谷歌帮忙翻译啦。<br>英文版在这里：  <a href="/some-thoughts-20200611/" title="Thoughts on personal growth（20200611）">Thoughts on personal growth（20200611）</a></p><h2 id="介绍"><a href="#介绍" class="headerlink" title="介绍"></a>介绍</h2><p>最近，我与我的经理和导师进行了一对一的交流，这里有些想法值得一提。</p><h2 id="影响力和说服力"><a href="#影响力和说服力" class="headerlink" title="影响力和说服力"></a>影响力和说服力</h2><p>成功地建立自己的影响力意味着您的老板和同事在关键的决策点上接受您的想法。我观察到，有些人在需要做出决定时会退后一步，但是一旦做出决定，他们就会抱怨该决定很糟糕，而他对此并不满意. 让我们假设一个会议场景，其中有几个建议供老板选择。如果他选择了一个由极有说服力的人吹捧的建议，尽管这在您看来是最糟糕的建议，但您仍然要承担决策的后果, 因为您没有尝试介入。</p><p>因此，在有正确观点的情况下，尝试整合演讲，说服，销售和谈判技巧以说服他人。逐步建立正面形象和品牌。虽然这些技能不是立即获得的，但是有了这种头脑，随着时间的流逝，如果不断地进行练习，它会逐渐提高。</p><h2 id="先问-为什么，再问-做什么"><a href="#先问-为什么，再问-做什么" class="headerlink" title="先问 为什么，再问 做什么"></a>先问 为什么，再问 做什么</h2><p>我知道讲WHY和WHAT的关系已经很陈词滥调，但只是想根据我的个人经验添加一些要点。例如，由于我在一个大团队中工作，经理通常在团队成员之间分配工作负载。当我被分配了一个jira时，通常是在一项服务中开发一项功能，最近，我倾向于将自己局限于分配的工作，而又不想了解其他人在做什么。但是，成长并能够在团队中承担更大责任的关键在于您了解端到端领域知识和业务流程的能力。将自己限制在一个狭窄的聚光灯下将禁止学习和理解全局，不利于个人成长。</p><p>因此，</p><ul><li>在分配任务时，始终积极地问为什么必须以某种方式完成任务，并与利益相关者从多个角度来理解它，包括业务分析师（BA），项目经理，客户。深入研究“什么”，“何时”和“如何”的细节，以了解所做出的决策，并有意见可对这些决策提供反馈。</li><li>其次，与队友交谈以了解他们正在做什么，以了解整个情况。</li><li>第三，进行产品修复时，即使您修复的是一行代码，也不要假设现有代码可以很好地与您的修复一起使用。始终仔细检查代码，并与BA核对预期行为。</li></ul><h2 id="让自己可见"><a href="#让自己可见" class="headerlink" title="让自己可见"></a>让自己可见</h2><p>简单粗暴的来讲，可见性会影响您未来的机会。在拥有100多名员工的部门中，您需要通过帮助他人并积极参加活动，成为他人需要解决问题或者提供建议的首选人。抓住机会向他人展示您的专业知识，并让他们尤其是管理团队认识到您的潜力。</p><p>让我们一起反思，总结和成长：)</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;懒得一字一句的翻译，就只能请谷歌帮忙翻译啦。&lt;br&gt;英文版在这里：  &lt;a href=&quot;/some-thoughts-20200611/&quot; title=&quot;Thoughts on personal growth（20200611）&quot;&gt;Thoughts on personal 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Career" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/categories/Career/"/>
    
    
      <category term="影响力" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/%E5%BD%B1%E5%93%8D%E5%8A%9B/"/>
    
      <category term="个人品牌" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E5%93%81%E7%89%8C/"/>
    
      <category term="说服力" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/%E8%AF%B4%E6%9C%8D%E5%8A%9B/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Thoughts on personal growth（20200611）</title>
    <link href="https://janicesg.github.io/some-thoughts-20200611/"/>
    <id>https://janicesg.github.io/some-thoughts-20200611/</id>
    <published>2020-06-11T09:05:53.021Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-13T14:13:33.982Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chinese Version：  <a href="/some-thoughts-20200611-chinese-version/" title="关于个人成长的思考（20200611）-谷歌机翻版">关于个人成长的思考（20200611）-谷歌机翻版</a></p><h2 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h2><p>Recently I had 1-on-1 catch ups with my manager and mentors, here are some thoughts worth noting down for my record.  </p><h2 id="Influence-and-Persuasion"><a href="#Influence-and-Persuasion" class="headerlink" title="Influence and Persuasion"></a>Influence and Persuasion</h2><p>To build one’s influence successfully means your bosses and peers buy in your ideas at critical decision points. I have observed that some people step back when decisions need to be made, but once decisions are made, they groan that the decision is poor, and he is not happy with it. Hypothetically, Let’s assume a scenario where several proposals are for the boss to pick. If he chooses one proposal touted by someone who is very good at persuasion, although it is the worst proposal in your opinion, you still have to bear with the consequences of decision made. Because you don’t try to step in. </p><p>Therefore, lean in when with a valid perspective, but try to integrate presentation, persuasion, selling, and negotiation skills to convince others. Gradually, the positive image and branding will build up. These skills are not acquired instantly, but with this mindset in head, it should gradually improve over time with consistent practice. </p><h2 id="Ask-WHY-then-WHAT"><a href="#Ask-WHY-then-WHAT" class="headerlink" title="Ask WHY, then WHAT"></a>Ask WHY, then WHAT</h2><p>I know the WHY and WHAT are already cliche, but just want to add some takeaways based on my personal experience. For example, because I work in a big team, and it is common for manager to split workloads among team members. when I was assigned with a jira, normally it is to develop a feature in one service, recently I tend to limit myself to assigned work, without wanting to learn about what others are doing. But the key to grow and be able to take on bigger responsibility in a team lies in your capability to understand the domain knowledge and business flows end to end. Limiting yourself to a narrow spotlight will prohibit learning and understanding the big picture, and detrimental to personal growth.</p><p>Therefore,</p><ul><li>When assigned with tasks, always actively ask why it has to be done in certain way, approach stakeholders to understand it from multiple perspectives, including Business Analyst(BA), Program Manager, Client. Dive into details on WHAT, WHEN and HOW, to learn about the decisions made, and have an opinion to give feedback on those decisions. </li><li>Secondly, talk with teammates to understand what they are working on to learn about the whole picture.</li><li>Thirdly, when making product fix, don’t assume the existing code will work with your fix perfectly well, even though you fix is one line of code. Always carefully scrutinize the code and check with BA on the expected behavior. </li></ul><h2 id="Make-yourself-visible"><a href="#Make-yourself-visible" class="headerlink" title="Make yourself visible"></a>Make yourself visible</h2><p>Visibility impacts your future opportunities, put it in a blunt but simple way. In a department with 100+ employees, become the go-to person of others by helping them and actively participating in events. Grab the opportunity to present your expertise to others, and let them especially management teams recognize your potential. </p><p>Let’s reflect, summarize, and grow together :)</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Chinese Version：  &lt;a href=&quot;/some-thoughts-20200611-chinese-version/&quot; title=&quot;关于个人成长的思考（20200611）-谷歌机翻版&quot;&gt;关于个人成长的思考（20200611）-谷歌机翻版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Career" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/categories/Career/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Spotlight" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/Spotlight/"/>
    
      <category term="Influence" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/Influence/"/>
    
      <category term="Persuasion" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/Persuasion/"/>
    
      <category term="Personal Branding" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/Personal-Branding/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Switzerland Trip in 2018</title>
    <link href="https://janicesg.github.io/switzerland-2018/"/>
    <id>https://janicesg.github.io/switzerland-2018/</id>
    <published>2020-05-09T11:48:22.708Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T06:27:33.247Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h2><p>I went to Switzerland on a two-week’s personal trip with my friend CM in the spring of 2018. Switzerland, is like a ‘Jungfrau’, who impressed me, a visitor from afar, with the breath-taking view and hospitable people. I was trying to be a vegetarian back then, so CM and I only had one meal with her old school friend in a local restaurant. We cooked and packed our meals for the rest of the trip, which is why there won’t be a lot of typical exotic food pictures below.<br>We planned to tour the whole country within 15 days, so we rent an airbnb studio in Basel, a small town located in the middle of Switzerland, and is accessible to all the tourist attractions via trains. Yet due to the fact that most of the tourist attractions are scattered around the country, and are 2~3 hrs away from our airbnb, we had to get up at 4:30am and leave the house at 5:30am to catch the earliest train, so that we wouldn’t behind our schedule. So the trip was actually quite tiring, not mentioning the wake up hours, we did a lot of hiking too.<br>CM is a great planner, and she managed to plan for most the day trips. She even wrote down the timings of each trains that we should take, and in case of missing any, she wrote down the previous and next train timing as well.</p><h2 id="Lugano"><a href="#Lugano" class="headerlink" title="Lugano"></a>Lugano</h2><p>We went to Lugano, the capital of the southest Cantone Ticino bordered with Italy via train, and it took about 3hrs from where we stay.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/lugano.jpg" width="720px"><br>The train station was high in the mountain, and we need to walk down the hill to the city.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/luganoBell.jpg" width="720px"><br>Before we boarded for our boat trip, we bumped into an open area event happening at the market center. There were performances of kids, including ballet, kpop dancing, and a children orchestra performance.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/dance.jpg" width="720px"><br>We took a boat to tour around the lake bordering with Italy, and the flag is even italian.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/italianflag.jpg" width="720px"><br>The boat trip lasted about 4hrs, our original plan was to visit the village across, however there was no time, thus we decided to walk around lugano for a while.</p><p>The Gelato is pretty authentic, they even offered Vegan flavor for CM. I got an vanilla flavor, and I had to admit it melts very fast in the middle of the hot early summer day.<br><img src="/switzerland-2018/gelato_1.jpg" width="720px"></p><p>To be continued……</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h2 id=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Introduction&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went to Switzerland on a two
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Travel" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/categories/Travel/"/>
    
    
      <category term="switzerland" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/switzerland/"/>
    
      <category term="travel" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/travel/"/>
    
      <category term="2018" scheme="https://janicesg.github.io/tags/2018/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
